The East St. Louis Race Riot of 1917 on Microfilm 5749 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
The East St. Louis Race Riot of 1917 on Microfilm
1917-1920
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
University Publications of America
5749 mf
0.89 cubic feet
8 microfilm reels
Records (documents), microfilm.
The public record on a murderous riot against Blacks sparked by the racial hatred and the uncertain economic conditions in post-World War I America.
5701416
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 13, 2019
Scope and Contents
The public record on a murderous riot against Blacks sparked by the racial hatred and the uncertain economic conditions in post-World War I America.
The complete Univeristy Publications of America guide to this microfilm may be accessed at: http://cisupa.proquest.com/ksc_assets/catalog/10728_EastStLouisRaceRiot1917.pdf
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arrangement
Series Volume I, 1917
Series Volume I continued, 1917
Series Volume II, 1917
Series Volume II continued, 1917
Series Volume III, 1917
Series Volume IV, 1917
Series Volume V, 1917
Series Volume VI, 1917
Series Volume VII, 1917
Series Volume VIII, 1917
Series Volume IX, 1917
Series Volume X, 1917
Series Volume XI, 1917
Series Volume XII, 1917
Series Volume XIII, 1917
Series Volume XIV, 1917
Series Volume XV, 1917
Series Volume XVI, 1917
Series Volume XVII, 1917
Series Volume XVIII, 1917
Series Volume XIX, 1917
Series Volume XX, 1917
Series Volume XXI, 1917
Series Volume XXII, 1917
Series Volume XXII continued, 1917
Series Volume XXIII, 1917
Series Exhibits, 1917
Series Board of Inquiry, Volume I, 1917
Series Board of Inquiry, Volume II, 1917
Series Related Reports and Records of the House Select Committee and Local Groups
Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
Series Witnesses on Behalf of the Defendant, 1919
Series Witnesses for the Defendant, 1919
Series Witnesses for the Defendant, 1919
Series Last day of the trial, 1919
Riots--Illinois--East Saint Louis; Race Discrimination--Illinois--East Saint Louis; Afro-Americans. Southern States. Migrations.; East Saint Louis (Ill.). Race relations.; East Saint Louis (Ill.)--East Relations; University Publications of America; Bundy, LeRoy; Rudwick, Elliot M., ed.
5701416
- Alphabetical Listing of Witnesses., 1917; 1 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  44 pp.
- Series Volume I, 1917
  October 18, 1917. pp 1-124.
  - Appointment of the Committee Index., 1917; 2 (Reel 1)
    8 pp.
  - Phillip W. Coyle, Traffic Manager, St. Louis Chamber of Commerce., 1917; 3 (Reel 1)
    pp5-42. 43 pp.
  - Frank J. Hunter, General Manager, Swift and Company, 1917; 4 (Reel 1)
    pp 61-98. 38 pp.
  - Charles Rogers, President, J.C. Grant Chemical Company@ and President, McMahon Transfer Company., 1917; 5 (Reel 1)
    pp 98-123. 26 pp.
- Series Volume I continued, 1917
  October 19, 1917. pp. 124-249.
  - Robert E. Conway, General Manager, Armour and Company, National Stock Yards., 1917; 6 (Reel 1)
    pp. 124-194. 68 pp.
  - Frank V. Hammar, Hammar Brothers, White Lead Company, 1917; 7 (Reel 1)
    pp 195-248. 54 pp.
  - Charles Rogers, Additional Statement., 1917; 8 (Reel 1)
    pp 248-249. 2 pp.
- Series Volume II, 1917
  October 20, 1917 pp 250-338.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 9 (Reel 1)
    2 pp.
  - Paul Y. Anderson, Reporter, St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1917; 10 (Reel 1)
    pp 250-338. 88 pp.
- Series Volume II continued, 1917
  October 22, 1917. pp 338-516.
  - Ben Beard, (Colored) Laborer, Aluminum Ore Plant., 1917; 11 (Reel 1)
    pp 338-343. 6 pp.
  - G.E. Popkess, Reporter, St. Louis Times., 1917; 12 (Reel 1)
    pp 383-428. 46 pp.
  - J.W. Paton, Manager, Morris and Company., 1917; 13 (Reel 1)
    pp 428-469. 42 pp.
  - Roy Albertson, Reporter, The East St. Louis Journal, 1917; 14 (Reel 1)
    pp 469-511. 43 pp.
  - J.C. Brady, Justice-of-the-Peace, East St. Louis., 1917; 15 (Reel 1)
    pp 511-516. 6 pp.
- Series Volume III, 1917
  October 23, 1917. pp 517-689.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 16 (Reel 1)
  - Roy Albertson, Testimony cont., 1917; 17 (Reel 1)
    pp 517-567. 51 pp.
  - L.W. Childress, President, Columbia Transfer Company, 1917; 18 (Reel 1)
    pp 567-572. 6 pp.
  - Robert J. Baylan, Reporter, East St. Louis Globe-Democrat., 1917; 19 (Reel 1)
    pp572-638. 66 pp.
  - John D. Roach, Supervisor, American Steel Industry., 1917; 20 (Reel 1)
    pp 638-672. 35 pp.
  - Calvin Cotton, (Colored) Teaming., 1917; 21 (Reel 1)
    pp 672-689. 19 pp.
- Series Volume IV, 1917
  October 24, 1917. pp 690-921.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 22 (Reel 1)
  - John P. Pero, Superintendent, Malleable Iron Company., 1917; 23 (Reel 1)
    pp 690-753. 63 pp.
  - S.O. Tripp, Colonel, Assistant Quartermaster General, National Guard, State of Illinois., 1917; 24 (Reel 1)
    pp 753-921. 169 pp.
- Series Volume V, 1917
  October 25, 1917. pp 922-1132
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 1 (Reel 2)
  - S.O. Tripp, Colonel, Testimony cont., 1917; 2 (Reel 2)
    pp 922-932 11 pp.
  - Frank S. Dickson, Adjutant General, Springfield Illinois, 1917; 3 (Reel 2)
    pp 932-1013 81 pp.
  - Frank E. Nulson, President, Missouri Malleable Iron Company., 1917; 4 (Reel 2)
    pp 1013-1056. 44 pp.
  - Maurice V. Joyce, Attorney at Law., 1917; 5 (Reel 2)
    pp 1056-1063 8 pp.
  - Thomas G. Hunter, (Colored) Physician and Surgeon., 1917; 6 (Reel 2)
    pp 1064-1105 42 pp.
  - W.H. Mills, (Colored) Police Officer., 1917; 7 (Reel 2)
    pp 1105-1119 15 pp.
  - W. Green, (Colored) Police Officer., 1917; 8 (Reel 2)
    pp 1119-1132 14 pp.
- Series Volume VI, 1917
  October 26, 1917. pp 1133-1345
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 9 (Reel 2)
  - John Eubanks, (Colored) Police Officer., 1917; 10 (Reel 2)
    pp 1133-1228 97 pp.
  - Dr. C.P. Renner, Coroner, St. Clair County., 1917; 11 (Reel 2)
    pp 1229-1294 66 pp.
  - Otto Nelson, (Colored) Police Officer., 1917; 12 (Reel 2)
    pp 1295-1345 51 pp.
- Series Volume VII, 1917
  October 27, 1917. pp 1346-1525
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 13 (Reel 2)
  - Dr. Lyman B. Bluitt@ Blewett, (Colored) Physician., 1917; 14 (Reel 2)
    pp 1346-1373 27 pp.
  - Mineola Magee, (Colored) Occupation Not Listed., 1917; 15 (Reel 2)
    pp 1373-1379. 6 pp.
  - William Roach, Sewer Commissioner, East St. Louis., 1917; 16 (Reel 2)
    pp 1381-1388 7 pp.
  - Robert R. Thomas, Cement Contractor., 1917; 17 (Reel 2)
    pp 1388-1407 19 pp.
  - Thomas J. Canavan, Real Estate, Loans, and Insurance, 1917; 18 (Reel 2)
    pp 1407-1503 96 pp.
  - C.B. Fox, General Superintendent, Aluminum Ore Company., 1917; 19 (Reel 2)
    pp 1504-1525. 21 pp.
- Series Volume VIII, 1917
  October 29, 1917. pp 1526-1743
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 20 (Reel 2)
  - C.B. Fox, Testimony cont., 1917; 21 (Reel 2)
    pp 1526-1690. 164 pp.
  - Dr. Albert B. McQuillan, Physician., 1917; 22 (Reel 2)
    pp 1600-1743 53 pp.
- Series Volume IX, 1917
  October 30, 1917. pp 1744-1946
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 23 (Reel 2)
  - John H. Richards, Deputy State Fire Marshal., 1917; 24 (Reel 2)
    pp 1744-1754 10 pp.
  - William Roach, Supervisor of Construction, National Stockyards Company., 1917; 25 (Reel 2)
    pp 1755-1784A 33 pp.
  - Exhibit: Data Submitted by William Roach., 1917; 26 (Reel 2)
    1 p.
  - Frank Weckenmeyer, Electrical Contractor., 1917; 27 (Reel 2)
    pp. 1785-1792 7 pp.
  - R.T. Rucker, Assistant Superintendent, Aluminum Ore Company., 1917; 28 (Reel 2)
    pp 1792-1860. 68 pp.
  - Exhibit: Copy of Grievances of the Aluminum Ore Employee Protective Association., 1917; 29 (Reel 2)
  - Joe D. Williamson, (Colored) Janitor., 1917; 30 (Reel 2)
    pp 1861-1862 2 pp.
  - Harry Kerr, District Organizer, American Federation of Labor., 1917; 31 (Reel 2)
    pp 1862-1946
- Series Volume X, 1917
  October 31, 1917. pp 1947-2166
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 1 (Reel 3)
  - Harry Kerr, Testimony cont., 1917; 2 (Reel 3)
    pp. 1947-2166. 69pp
  - Earl W. Jimerson, Financial Secretary and Business Agent, Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America@ Member, County Board of Supervisors., 1917; 3 (Reel 3)
    pp 2016-2136. 120pp
  - Philip Wolf, Worker, Aluminum Ore Company, Valley Steel Plant., 1917; 4 (Reel 3)
    pp 2136-2166. 30pp
- Series Volume XI, 1917
  November 1, 1917. pp 2167-2390
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 5 (Reel 3)
  - Philip Wolf, Testimony cont., 1917; 6 (Reel 3)
    pp2167-2348. 181pp
  - William Hawkins, (Colored) Occupation Not Listed., 1917; 7 (Reel 3)
    pp 2348-2364. 16pp
  - Alois Towers, Labor Representative, Belleville., 1917; 8 (Reel 3)
    pp 2364-2390. 26pp
- Series Volume XII, 1917
  November 2, 1917. pp 2391-2595
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 9 (Reel 3)
  - Alois Towers, Testimony cont., 1917; 10 (Reel 3)
    pp 2391-2552. 161pp
  - William Hawkins, Testimony cont., 1917; 11 (Reel 3)
    pp 2552-2553. 1p
  - Alois Towers, Testimony cont., 1917; 12 (Reel 3)
    pp 2553-2555. 2pp
  - Stephen F. Porter, Motorman, East St. Louis and Suburban Street Car Company, 1917; 13 (Reel 3)
    pp 2555-2567. 12pp
  - Harry Kerr, Additional Statement., 1917; 14 (Reel 3)
    pp 2567-2570. 3 pp.
  - Exhibit: Invitation to Labor Delegates to Attend Meeting of May 23, 1917., 15 (Reel 3)
  - Alois Towers, Testimony cont., 1917; 16 (Reel 3)
    pp2370-2595. 25pp
- Series Volume XIII, 1917
  November 3, 1917. pp 2596-2773
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 17 (Reel 3)
  - Clarence Eugene Pope, Chairman, Committee of One Hundred., 1917; 18 (Reel 3)
    pp 2596-2773. 177 pp.
  - Exhibit: Resolution of the Committee of One Hundred., 1917; 19 (Reel 3)
- Series Volume XIV, 1917
  November, 1917. pp 2774-2981
  - Clarence Eugene Pope, Testimony cont., 1917; 20 (Reel 3)
    pp2774-2777. 3pp
  - James M. Kelley, Controller, City of East St. Louis, 1917; 21 (Reel 3)
    pp 2777-2876. 99pp
  - S.J. Cashel, City Treasurer, City of East St. Louis, 1917; 22 (Reel 3)
    pp 2876-2981. 105 pp.
- Series Volume XV, 1917
  November 7, 1917. pp 2982-3247
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 1 (Reel 4)
  - Dan McGlynn, Attorney at Law., 1917; 2 (Reel 4)
    pp 2983-3109. 123 pp.
  - H.H. Jost, Cashier, Southern Illinois National Bank., 1917; 3 (Reel 4)
    pp 3110-3117. 7 pp.
  - Exhibit: Aluminum Ore Employees Protective Association Account., 1917; 4 (Reel 4)
  - Dan McGlynn, Testimony cont., 1917; 5 (Reel 4)
    pp 3117-3118. 1 p.
  - Edward F. Mason, Secretary, Central Body, and Machinists Union., 1917; 6 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3118-3198. 80 pp.
  - Exhibit: Minutes of Central Trades and Labor Union., 1917; 7 (Reel 4)
  - H.H. Jost, Testimony cont., 1917; 8 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3198-3200. 2 pp.
  - James W. Kirk, Editor, The East St. Louis Journal., 1917; 9 (Reel 4)
    pp3200-3247. 47 pp.
  - Exhibit: "Mollman Workers Dine" The East St. Louis Journal, April 14, 1917., 10 (Reel 4)
- Series Volume XVI, 1917
  October 8, 1917. pp 3248-3458
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 11 (Reel 4)
  - Lee Cox, (Colored) Concrete Worker., 1917; 12 (Reel 4)
    pp 3258-3261. 13 pp.
  - George Thornton, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 13 (Reel 4)
    pp 3261-3266. 5 pp.
  - William James Perkins, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 14 (Reel 4)
    pp 3266-3271. 5 pp.
  - Tommy Lee Bogan, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 15 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3272-3278. 6 pp.
  - Clarence Eugene Pope, Testimony cont., 1917; 16 (Reel 4)
    pp 3278-3303. 25 pp.
  - D.S. Allim, Laborer, Mobile and Ohio Railroad Company., 1917; 17 (Reel 4)
    pp 3304-3329. 25pp
  - Eddie B. Griffin, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 18 (Reel 4)
    pp 3329-3338. 9 pp.
  - Baskin Carter, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 19 (Reel 4)
    pp 3339-3351. 12 pp.
  - Peter Baker, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 20 (Reel 4)
    pp 3352-3355. 3 pp.
  - Jim Houston, (Colored Laborer., 1917; 21 (Reel 4)
    pp 3352-3355. 1 p.
  - William B. Wood, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 22 (Reel 4)
    pp3352-3355. 1 p.
  - Tommy Crawford, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 23 (Reel 4)
  - Napoleon Griffin, (Colored) Laborer., 1917; 24 (Reel 4)
    pp 3352-3355. 5 pp.
  - J.W. Kirk, Testimony cont., 1917; 25 (Reel 4)
    pp 3356-3387. 31 pp.
  - Fred Pellet, Machinist, Niedring House Plant, 1917; 26 (Reel 4)
    pp 3387-3409. 22 pp.
  - Charles Nagel, Attorney at Law, 1917; 27 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3409-3417. 8 pp.
  - Russell Townsend, Justice-of-the-Peace, East St. Louis., 1917; 28 (Reel 4)
    pp 3417-3458. 41 pp.
- Series Volume XVII, 1917
  November 9, 1917. pp. 3459-3658
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 29 (Reel 4)
  - August Schlafly, Banking and Farming., 1917; 30 (Reel 4)
    pp 3459-3498. 39 pp.
  - George W. Allison, Minister, First Baptist Church., 1917; 31 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3498-3658. 160 pp.
- Series Volume XVIII, 1917
  November 10, 1917. pp. 3659-3839
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 32 (Reel 4)
  - George W. Allison, Testimony cont., 1917; 33 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3659-3786. 127 pp.
  - James M. Kelley, Testimony cont., 1917; 34 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3786-3787. 1 p.
  - Paul Y. Anderson, Testimony cont., 1917; 35 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3787-3837. 50 pp.
  - N.L. Coley, Attorney at Law., 1917; 36 (Reel 4)
    pp 3837-3839. 2 pp.
- Series Volume XIX, 1917
  November 12, 1917. pp. 3840-4062
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 37 (Reel 4)
  - Frank I. Marks, Pawn Broker., 1917; 38 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3840-3884. 44 pp.
  - Ferdinand Schwartz, Printer and Paper Hanger., 1917; 39 (Reel 4)
    pp.3885-3899. 14 pp.
  - E.M. Sorrells, Superintendent, River Navigation Department, Aluminum Ore Company., 1917; 40 (Reel 4)
    pp. 3900-3971. 71 pp.
  - Stewart Campbell, Superintendent, State Free Employment Office., 1917; 41 (Reel 4)
    pp 3972-2987. 15 pp.
  - Emmett P. Griffin, Superintendent and Chief Engineer, East St. Louis., 1917; 42 (Reel 4)
    pp 3987-3991. 4 pp.
  - Stewart Campbell, Testimony cont., 1917; 43 (Reel 4)
    pp 3991-4003. 13 pp.
  - George W. Allison, Testimony cont., 1917; 44 (Reel 4)
    pp.4003-4004. 1 p.
  - E.M. Sorrells, Testimony cont., 1917; 45 (Reel 4)
    pp. 4005-4062. 57 pp.
  - Exhibits: Resignation of C.B. Fox from the Chamber of Commerce, May 11, 1917., 46 (Reel 4)
  - Letter from C.B. Fox to M.V. Joyce, May 15, 1917., 47 (Reel 4)
- Series Volume XX, 1917
  November 13, 1917. pp 4063-4265.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 1 (Reel 5)
  - W.A. Miller, Railroad YMCA., 1917; 2 (Reel 5)
    pp 4063-4127. 64 pp.
  - A.B. Hendry, Reporter, The Post-Dispatch., 1917; 3 (Reel 5)
    pp 4128-4151. 23 pp.
  - J.W. Edmonson, (Colored) Sergeant of Police., 1917; 4 (Reel 5)
    pp 4151-4185. 34 pp.
  - J.J. Kane, Collector and City Salesman, Wagner Brewery of Granite City., 1917; 5 (Reel 5)
    pp 4185-4265. 80 pp.
- Series Volume XXI, 1917
  November 14, 1917. pp. 4266-4432.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 6 (Reel 5)
  - Edward J. Brennan, Special Agent, Bureau of Investigation, Department of Justice, East St. Louis., 1917; 7 (Reel 5)
    pp 4266-4271. 5 pp.
  - Frank I. Marks, Testimony cont., 1917; 8 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4271-4306. 35 pp.
  - Exhibit: List of Bondsmen Furnished by Frank I. Marks., 1917; 9 (Reel 5)
  - Robert E. Johns, Business Agent for Carpenters., 1917; 10 (Reel 5)
    pp 4306-4380. 74 pp.
  - M.R. Bevington, Attorney for the Government., 1917; 11 (Reel 5)
    pp 4381-4412. 32 pp.
  - Reverend Father Christopher Goetz, Catholic Clergymen., 1917; 12 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4412-4420. 8 pp.
  - Paul Y. Anderson, Testimony cont., 1917; 13 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4421-4432. 12 pp.
  - Exhibit: Dramshop Licenses Issued for Fourth Quarter, Year 1917., 14 (Reel 5)
- Series Volume XXII, 1917
  November 15, 1917. pp. 4433-4646.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 15 (Reel 5)
  - W.A. Miller, Testimony cont., 1917; 16 (Reel 5)
    p. 4433. 1 p.
  - Fred Gressing, Hardware Merchandise., 1917; 17 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4433-4438. 5 pp.
  - H.F. Bader, Former Mayor, East St. Louis, 1917; 18 (Reel 5)
    pp 4438-4502. 64 pp.
  - Isaac Cohen, Commission Business, Buyer of Metal, Iron and Metal Company., 1917; 19 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4503-4521. 18 pp.
  - George W. Allison, Testimony cont., 1917; 20 (Reel 5)
    pp 4522-4529. 7 pp.
  - D.W. Kaufman, Real Estate and Insurance@ Election Commissioner., 1917; 21 (Reel 5)
    pp 4530-4542. 12 pp.
  - J.C. Brady, Testimony cont., 1917; 22 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4542-4545. 3 pp.
  - J.W. Kaufman, Testimony cont., 1917; 23 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4545-4579. 34 pp.
  - Irwin Rout, Secretary, Industrial Branch, YMCA., 1917; 24 (Reel 5)
    4579-4585. 6 pp.
  - H.H. Hunsaker, Switchman and Former Jeweler., 1917; 25 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4586-4592. 6 pp.
  - E.J. Verlie, Attorney at Law., 1917; 26 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4592-4617. 25 pp.
  - A.H. Thomas, (Colored) Watchman and Assistant Timekeeper, Terminal Railroad Association., 1917; 27 (Reel 5)
    pp 4617-4631. 14 pp.
  - Paul Y. Anderson, Testimony cont., 1917; 28 (Reel 5)
    4631-4646. 15 pp.
- Series Volume XXII continued, 1917
  November 16, 1917. pp 4646-4664.
  - Robert W. Sikking, Real Estate@ Former Clerk, East Side Levee and Sanitary Board., 1917; 29 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4646-4652. 6 pp.
  - David F. Barrett, Reporter, St. Louis Star., 1917; 30 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4653-4654. 2 pp.
  - Martin Weiss, Attorney at Law., 1917; 31 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4654-4661. 7 pp.
  - Fred Gressing, Testimony cont., 1917; 32 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4661-4664. 3 pp.
  - Statement of Myrtle Gardner, Occupation not listed, 1917; 33 (Reel 5)
    no pp. 31 pp.
  - Statement of Dorabel Crook, Occupation Not Listed., 1917; 34 (Reel 5)
    no pp. 17 pp.
- Series Volume XXIII, 1917
  November 17, 1917. pp 4710-4875.
  - Folder and Index., 1917; 35 (Reel 5)
  - People v. Davey Crook and People v. Grace Yent, Mary Don, Emma Roe, and Ruby Nelson., 1917; 36 (Reel 5)
    pp 4710-4711. 15 pp.
  - Eli Chrisan, Worked in a Saloon., 1917; 37 (Reel 5)
    pp 4711-4750. 39 pp.
  - Anthony Stocker, Police Officer., 1917; 38 (Reel 5)
    pp 4750-4774. 24 pp.
  - Michael O'Brien, Deputy Sheriff, 1917; 39 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4774-4793. 19 pp.
  - Ruby Nelson, Occupation Not Listed, 1917; 40 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4793-4801. 8 pp.
  - Mrs. Grace Yent, Occupation Not Listed., 1917; 41 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4801-4814. 13 pp.
  - Deborah Crook, Manager, Second Hand Store., 1917; 42 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4815-4825. 10 pp.
  - George A. Boyle, Judge., 1917; 43 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4825-4827. 2 pp.
  - R.R. Aldrich, City Detective., 1917; 44 (Reel 5)
    pp 4827-4830. 3 pp.
  - McCauley Baird, Assistant United States Attorney., 1917; 45 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4834-4839. 5 pp.
  - William Crome, Police Chauffeur, and Police Department Mechanic., 1917; 46 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4840-4841. 2 pp.
  - Eli Chrisan, Testimony cont., 1917; 47 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4841-4842. 2 pp.
  - Charles A. Karch, Attorney at Law., 1917; 48 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4842-4846. 4 pp.
  - Michael O'Brien, Testimony cont., 1917; 49 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4846-4847. 2 pp.
  - Arguments: Mr. Wolcott, 1917; 50 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4847-4849. 3 pp.
  - Mr. Coley, 1917; 51 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4840-4859. 10 pp.
  - Mr. Borders., 1917; 52 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4859-4864. 6 pp.
  - Mr. Wolcott., 1917; 53 (Reel 5)
    pp. 4864-4875. 12 pp.
- Series Exhibits, 1917
  - Exhibit A: Copy of Report to Governor, by Colonel S.O. Tripp, Race Riot, East St. Louis, Illinois., 1917; 1 (Reel 6)
    October 25, 1917. 53 pp.
  - Exhibit B: Sheriff Office, St. Clair County, Logan P. Mellon, Sheriff., 1917; 2 (Reel 6)
    July 2, 1917. 1 p.
  - Exhibit C: City of East St. Louis, Illinois, Executive Department, Fred W. Mollman, Mayor., 1917; 3 (Reel 6)
  - Exhibit D: Time Sheet for National Guard and Statement by Commanding Officers., 1917; 4 (Reel 6)
    July 2, 3, and 4, 1917. 5 pp.
  - Exhibit E., 1917; 5 (Reel 6)
  - Street Maps of East St. Louis., 1917; 6 (Reel 6)
    36 pp.
  - Letter from the Board of Inquiry to the Adjutant General., 1917; 7 (Reel 6)
    August 2, 1917. 18 pp.
- Series Board of Inquiry, Volume I, 1917
  - Proceedings, 1917; 8 (Reel 6)
    July 16, 1917. 229 pp.
  - Proceedings, 1917; 9 (Reel 6)
    July 17, 1917. 242 pp.
- Series Board of Inquiry, Volume II, 1917
  - Proceedings, 1917; 10 (Reel 6)
    July 18, 1917. 260 pp.
- Series Related Reports and Records of the House Select Committee and Local Groups
  - People v. LeRoy Bundy File: Draft of the Committee's Final Report., 1 (Reel 7)
    64 pp.
  - Committee Expenditures and Legal and Administrative Correspondence., 2 (Reel 7)
    45 pp.
  - East St. Louis Race Riot of 1917--List of Persons Implicated., 3 (Reel 7)
    6 pp.
  - Report of the Treasurer of East St. Louis., 4 (Reel 7)
    35 pp.
  - Pictures., 5 (Reel 7)
    39 pp.
  - Report of the Illinois State Council of Defense on the Race Riots at East St. Louis, by Its Committee on Labor., 6 (Reel 7)
    16 pp.
  - Hearings of the Labor Committee of the Illinois State Council of Defense., 7 (Reel 7)
    187 pp.
  - Report of the Grand Jury of St. Clair County, Illinois., 8 (Reel 7)
    9 pp.
  - Petition of the Citizens of East St. Louis., 9 (Reel 7)
    27 pp.
  - People vs. LeRoy Bundy, No. 13366, Opinion Filed December 21, 1920, in Reports of Cases at Law and in Chancery Argued and Determined in Supreme Court of Illinois., 10 (Reel 7)
    1p
  - Circuit Coart, State of Illinois, County of Monroe., 11 (Reel 7)
  - Ind Initial Proceedings, 1919; 12 (Reel 7)
    March 17, 1919, 14 pp.
  - Indictment of Murder, 13 (Reel 7)
  - Change of Venue from St. Clair County., 14 (Reel 7)
  - Endorsements, 15 (Reel 7)
- Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
  March 18, 1919.
  - Edward P. Keshner., 1919; 16 (Reel 7)
    7 pp.
  - Charles J. Miller., 1919; 17 (Reel 7)
    23 pp.
  - John Stapp., 1919; 18 (Reel 7)
    38 pp.
  - Barbara Stapp., 1919; 19 (Reel 7)
    43 pp.
  - John M. Hubert., 1919; 20 (Reel 7)
    25 pp.
  - Mrs. George Wodley., 1919; 21 (Reel 7)
    3 pp.
  - Mrs. Mary Fisher., 1919; 22 (Reel 7)
  - Jacob Shucart., 1919; 23 (Reel 7)
    13 pp.
  - Henry L. Kridwig., 1919; 24 (Reel 7)
  - L.G. Miller., 1919; 25 (Reel 7)
  - Andrew J. Gaa., 1919; 26 (Reel 7)
    21 pp.
  - Fred Henley., 1919; 27 (Reel 7)
    4 pp.
  - Frank Reedy., 1919; 28 (Reel 7)
    15 pp.
- Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
  March 21, 1919.
  - Mrs. George W. Wodley, Testimony continued., 1919; 29 (Reel 7)
  - Gus Masserang., 1919; 30 (Reel 7)
    55 pp.
  - George Vattner., 1919; 31 (Reel 7)
  - William Hutter., 1919; 32 (Reel 7)
    20 pp.
  - Patrick Cullinane., 1919; 33 (Reel 7)
    18 pp.
  - Oscar Hobbs., 1919; 34 (Reel 7)
  - George Vattner, Testimony continued., 1919; 35 (Reel 7)
  - Edward Wilson., 1919; 36 (Reel 7)
    41 pp.
  - Thomas Barrett., 1919; 37 (Reel 7)
- Series Witnesses on Behalf of the People, 1919
  March 24, 1919.
  - Dr. C.P. Renner., 1919; 38 (Reel 7)
  - William Tojo., 1919; 39 (Reel 7)
    32 pp.
  - Fred Peleate., 1919; 1 (Reel 8)
    61pp.
  - George Vattner, Testimony cont., 1919; 2 (Reel 8)
    7pp.
  - Earl A. Bateman., 1919; 3 (Reel 8)
    35pp.
  - Clarence Dixon., 1919; 4 (Reel 8)
    20pp.
  - Motion to Deny Testimony of Witness, 1919; 5 (Reel 8)
    March 25, 1919. 2pp.
  - Andrew J. Gaa., 5 (Reel 8)
- Series Witnesses on Behalf of the Defendant, 1919
  March 25, 1919.
  - J.E. Weinel., 1919; 6 (Reel 8)
    18pp.
  - Forrest Crawford., 1919; 7 (Reel 8)
  - Frank Adams., 1919; 8 (Reel 8)
    10pp.
  - John Owens., 1919; 9 (Reel 8)
    14pp.
  - Mrs. John Owens., 1919; 10 (Reel 8)
  - Henry Brown., 1919; 11 (Reel 8)
    5pp.
  - Finis Ernst., 1919; 12 (Reel 8)
  - Buddie Bell., 1919; 13 (Reel 8)
    28pp.
  - William Red., 1919; 14 (Reel 8)
    17pp.
  - Mat Hayes., 1919; 15 (Reel 8)
    19pp.
  - Joe Wilson., 1919; 16 (Reel 8)
  - N.W. Pardon., 1919; 17 (Reel 8)